Brian Lego

Full-Stack Software Engineer

New York City, NY 10032 | → 757-705-4436 | □ legobw@gmail.com https://brianwlego.com

JOB TITLE

Web Developer with a Bachelor's degree and a background in the performing arts. Possesses strong skills in team-building and collaboration to facilitate a common goal. I am used to working under pressure and multitasking with accuracy and efficiency. Within web development I plan to expand on my past experiences to be a vital, useful and passionate part of any dev team.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

QuizCard

A study aid that uses Quizzes and FlashCards to help students. Allows them to also create their own Quizzes/FlashCards for a more specialized experience.

- Built with a React frontend and Rails API backend
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Integrated Redux to allow for easy CRUD action of global state
- Used Active Storage and AWS s3 tech to easily store files uploaded by users
- Implemented pagination within scrollable div's to allow for lighter fetching from the backend API

!fcebook

A social media application that allows users to 'follow' friends, make posts, and comment on friend's posts.

- Built with a React frontend and Rails API backend
- Used Active Storage and AWS s3 tech to easily store files uploaded by users
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Integrated Action Serializers to allow for customized return data

Cocktail Companion

Static application which allows users to search cocktails based on ingredients.

- Built with vanilla Javascript and a Rails backend
- Utilized outside API to provide a large dataset
- Styled using basic CSS and JS event listeners for manipulation

SKILLS

Proficient: Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Object-Orientation (Mapping)

Exposure: AWS - s3, SQL, Postgresql

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Carnival UK Southampton, UK Singer/Dancer 06/2018 - 02/2020

- Collaborated within a cast and with team members to perform a full-scale production show
- Interacted with guests on a personal level to provide pleasant experiences onboard
- Facilitated safety trainings by directing guests on safety protocols

Celebrity Cruises Miami, FL Dancer 09/2015 - 05/2016

- Worked within a cast to perform 3 full scale production show
- Taught ballroom dance classes to guests by instructing and demonstrating appropriate level steps
- Assisted in ship operation as directed by upper management

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Manhattan, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript 07/ 2020 - 10/2020

Florida State University Tallahassee, FL BFA - Musical Theatre 06/2015